# DIANA K. PEREZ LOPEZ

 $\begin{array}{l} diana.perezlopez@yale.edu\\ dk.perez10@outlook.com \end{array}$ 

Phone: (+1) 475 227 9497

## Profile

I am a Pre-Doctoral fellow at the Yale Economic Growth Center, working with Professor Orazio Attanasio on child development and measurement in Economics. I have outstanding econometrics and coding skills. I am primarily interested in approaching inequality problems through empirical work using reduced form and structural approaches. My interests include child development, education, labor, measurement, and gender economics.

### **EDUCATION**

Spring 2021	M.A. Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia cum laude, GPA 4.72 out of 5, ranked 2 out of 38
	Thesis: "'Am I not good at it or am I not good at all?' STEM gender gaps
G	in higher education." (Grade: 5 out of 5, coded as Approved for COVID-19)
Spring 2019	B.A. Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia
	Minor in Management, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia
Awards	
2021	Placed in the top 3% of the previous 5 years of graduates in the M.A. in
	economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia (cum laude)
2018	Placed in the top $1\%$ in the Colombian higher education examinations (Saber-
	Pro)

# RELATED ADVANCED COURSEWORK

Yale University: Real Analysis (A, 3.98 out of 4); Universidad de los Andes, Colombia: Advanced Econometrics (5 out of 5)  $\cdot$  Econometrics and Machine Learning (5 out of 5)  $\cdot$  Long-Run Advanced Macroeconomics (4.6 out of 5)  $\cdot$  Advanced Microeconomics Game Theory (4.5 out of 5)  $\cdot$ 

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Yale Economic Growth Center and Department of Economics

 $Pre ext{-}Doctoral/Postgraduate fellow$ 

Aug. 2021 - Present Principal investigator: Orazio Attanasio

Research Assistant

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021 Principal investigator: Orazio Attanasio

### Department of Economics and CEDE, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Research Assistant

May 2019 - Mar. 2021 Principal investigator: Raquel Bernal Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2019 Principal investigator: Fabio Sanchez Principal investigator: Diego Amador

#### Department of Economics, Princeton University

Research Assistant

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020 Principal investigator: Micaela Sviatschi

## Work in Progress

"The Role of Maternal and Paternal Inputs on Child Development: Evidence from a Randomized Controlled Trial in Rwanda." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Theresa Betancourt*, *Sarah K. G. Jensen*, and *Matias Placencio-Castro*.

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

### Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Graduate Teacher Assistant

Spring 2019 - Spring 2021 Advanced Econometrics (masters); Prof. Raquel Bernal and

Prof. Manuel Fernandez

Fall 2019 - Fall 2020 Behavioral Economics (undergraduate); *Prof. Andres Moya* 

Spring 2019 - Summer 2019 Forecasting (masters); Prof. Daniel Wills

Summer 2019 Advanced Impact Evaluation on Complex Models (masters);

Prof. Sergio Urzua

Undergraduate Teacher Assistant

Fall 2017 Econometrics (undergraduate)

Spring 2017 Probability and Statistics 1 (undergraduate)

### SUMMER SCHOOLS AND COMMUNITY WORK

Fluent

Nov. 2019	RIDGE Summer School in Economics			
Sep. 2019	Community work: Translation of "CORE: The Economy" to Spanish			
Fall 2018	Community work, "Programa Progresa Fenicia": School tutoring to low-			
	income school-aged children			

# SKILLS

English

Stata and Latex	Advanced	R and Matlab	Intermediate
Languages			

Spanish

Native Language

<sup>&</sup>quot;'Am I not good at it or am I not good at all?" STEM gender gaps in higher education."

<sup>&</sup>quot;Measuring Impacts in Early Child Development Interventions." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Sarah Cattan*, *Sharon Wolf*, *Matias Placencio-Castro*, and *Marta Rubio-Codina*.

<sup>&</sup>quot;Estimating the Production Function of Human Capital in India." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Costas Meghir*, *Pamela Jervis*, and Alessandro Toppeta.

# REFERENCES

Raquel Bernal President and Full Professor of Economics, Universidad de Los Andes,

Colombia

rbernal@uniandes.edu.co

Orazio Attanasio Cowles Professor of Economics, Yale University

orazio.attanasio@yale.edu

Micaela Sviatschi Assistant Professor of Economics, Princeton University

msviatschi@princeton.edu

Diego Amador Research Scientist, Texas Policy Lab, Rice University

diego.amador.o@gmail.com